Welcome, everybody to the last day of week three.
3주 차 마지막 날에 오신 걸 환영합니다, 여러분
Week three.
3주 차예요
Day five.
5일째예요
We're here already wrapping up open source model inference with hugging face.
오픈 소스 모델 추론을 얼굴 껴안기와 함께 마무리하고 있어요
And today, today is the day that you're going pro.
오늘은 프로가 되는 날이에요
Today is the day when we're putting together everything you've learned in the last four days of lectures
오늘은 지난 나흘간 여러분이 배운 모든 걸 한데 모아 아주 훌륭하고 흥미진진한
and really solidifying it with an excellent, uh, juicy project, a business project which is going
사업 프로젝트로 굳건히 다지는 날입니다 이 분야에서 진정한 경험을 쌓을 수 있는 사업 프로젝트죠
to give you some, some true experience in the field, what you can do already, if you don't mind me
여러분이 이미 할 수 있는 일요 한 번 더 말해도 괜찮으시다면 개척자
telling you one more time, you can code with frontier models.
모델을 코딩할 수 있어요
You can build AI assistants with tools, multi-modality, generating images, making sounds.
툴을 이용한 다단계 인공지능 보조를 만들 수 있습니다 이미지 생성, 소리 생성 등이죠
Uh, and you can use pipelines, tokenizers and models within the hugging face Transformers library.
파이프라인, 토큰마이저, 모델을 포옹 트랜스포머 라이브러리에서 사용하세요
Today, you're going to be even more confident with Tokenizers and models.
오늘은 토큰저와 모델에 대해 더 잘 알게 될 거예요
You're going to be able to run inference across open source models with ease, and you're going to have
오픈 소스 모델을 쉽게 추론할 수 있을 겁니다 프론티어와 오픈
implemented an LLM solution combining frontier and open source models together into one nice package.
소스 모델을 결합한 LLM 솔루션을 구현해 하나의 멋진 패키지로 만들 수 있고요
There's also going to be a good business challenge for you to keep working on this, so let's get started.
Get it을 계속하는 데 좋은 사업 과제도 있을 거예요 그럼 시작하죠
The business problem that we have is a feature that is in many applications that we all know, and so
우리가 가진 비즈니스 문제는 우리가 아는 많은 응용 프로그램에 있는 기능이에요
it's a good, real kind of product.
좋은 종류의 진짜 제품이죠
We want to build a solution that can create minutes of meetings including things like actions and owners
작업이나 소유주 같은 걸 포함해 회의록을 만들 수 있는 솔루션을 구축하고
and so on.
싶어요
Uh, it will be able to take an audio recording and then use a frontier model, use an API to convert
오디오 레코딩을 프론티어 모델로 사용할 수 있고 API를 이용해 오디오를 텍스트로 변환할
the audio to text.
수 있죠
It's actually a task that I had given you as a follow on exercise from one of the projects last week,
지난주에 진행한 프로젝트에서 받은 후속 작업으로 드린 거예요 이미 실험해
so you may have already experimented with this, but if not, we're going to do it together.
보셨을 수도 있지만 아니라면 같이 해 보죠
We're going to call a frontier model to convert audio to text.
음향을 텍스트로 변환하는 개척자 모델을 부를 거예요
We are then going to use an open source model to turn that text into meeting minutes, summarizing it,
그런 다음 오픈 소스 모델을 사용해 그 텍스트를 회의록으로 바꾸고 요약하고
plucking out actions and owners and the like.
행동과 소유주 등을 추려내죠
And we will stream back results and show them in markdown.
결과를 스트리밍해서 할인된 걸 보여드릴게요
So these these are the activities we're going to do.
이게 우리가 할 활동이에요
That's how we're going to put it together.
그렇게 Put을 짜는 거예요
And it's going to build a product that will be useful.
유용한 제품을 만들 거예요
This is what we want to come up with.
이런 걸 만들고 싶었어요
We want to be able to have a solution that produces minutes like this with discussion points, takeaways,
이와 같은 솔루션을 만들고 싶습니다. 토론 포인트, 포장 포인트, 액션
action items, and as the input data to start with the resource that we'll be using.
아이템, 입력 데이터 등을 만들어서 사용할 리소스로 시작하는 솔루션이죠.
There are audio files of publicly available council meetings from councils across the US available on
미국 전역의 자치 위원회가 공개적으로 연 의회 회의에 참석한 음성 파일도 있어요
And that is where we'll begin.
거기서부터 시작하죠
I've already downloaded one of the audio files and taken a chunk out of it.
이미 오디오 파일 하나를 다운로드해서 일부를 잘라냈어요
In the interest of time, we'll do just a piece of the Denver City Council meeting rather than the whole
시간 관계상 덴버시 의회 회의 일부만 진행하도록 하죠 전체 회의
meeting.
말고요
But the idea is that that's going to help us show that it works.
하지만 그렇게 하면 작동한다는 걸 보여줄 수 있어요
And then perhaps this is something that you'll be able to use for your own meetings, for real, when
실제 상품이 출시됐을 때 여러분의 회의에서
we have a working product.
사용할 수 있을 거예요
So without further ado, let's go to Google Colab and let's build our application.
구글 Colab으로 가서 응용 프로그램을 만들어보죠